### Ricardo Moura Vargas | Frontend Developer

I consider my self an honest and hardworking person. I am creative and I love to learn, I'm always looking for opportunities to learn new technologies and ideas. I'm also love to meet people and new places, this curiosity lead me to move to Ireland where I lived and studied english for 3 years.

As a developer, I've been working with web development for 7 years and I also have 1 year of experience developing native android apps. Nowadays I focused in frontend development.

**Website**: <a href="https://ricardomvargas.github.io/">https://ricardomvargas.github.io/</a> **GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/ricardomvargas">https://github.com/ricardomvargas</a>

**Linkedin:** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardo-m-vargas/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardo-m-vargas/</a>

Phone (whatsapp): + 55 41 99128-8920 E-mail: mvargas.ricardo@gmail.com

#### Tech skills

- Web development with: HTML, CSS, SASS, Material UI and Bootstrap.
- Programming pages and components with: Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, React-router, React-intl, styled-components, feeth and axios.
- Testing with: Jest and React testing library.
- Desing: Basic Adobe Illustrador knowloged.
- Basic backend development experience with: .NET/C#, PHP and Node JS.
- Other tools: git, yarn/npm, Jira and Bitbucket.
- Experience working in agile teams with Kanban and Scrum.

#### **Soft Skills**

- · Good communications skills.
- · Focused in solving problems.
- Flexible: I'm not afraid to leave my comfort zone to help or learn.
- Native portuguese speaker with advanced english level.
- Team work spirit.
- Mind opened and respectful.
- I'm take responsibility for my acts and I'm not shy to admit my mistakes.

# **Education**

May 2020	Learning TypeScript	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Apr. 2020	Learning ECMA Script 6 (2016)	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Mar. 2020	Bootstrap 4 Essential Training	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Apr. 2020	React: React Router	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Mar. 2020	Node.js Essential Training	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Jan. 2020	Vue.js Essential Training	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Jan. 2020	PHP with MySQL Essential Training: 1 The Basics	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Jan. 2020	React: SPAs	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Oct. 2019	React.js: Building an Interface (2019)	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Sep. 2019	React for Web Designers (2018)	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Aug. 2019	Learning React	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
2017 - 2018	English Language (Advanced)	Liffey College, Dublin - Ireland
2016 - 2017	English Language (Intermediate)	Liffey College, Dublin - Ireland
2015 - 2016	English Language (Basic)	English Studio, Dublin - Ireland
2012 - 2015	System Information (not finished)	Centro Universitário de Vila Velha
2013	Android App Development Essential Trainning	Lynda.com
2013	Developing android apps	Visure Treinamentos, Vitória
2012	Developing Web Applications Using VS 2008	Mindworks, Vitória
2007	High School	CIE, Governador Valadares

(\*) Certificates are visible in my linkedin profile.

# **Work Experience**

#### Senior Frontend developer | Oct. 2021 to current date | Paraná Banco

I am responsible for projects that serve the military and for attracting new customers.

- Doing brainstorming to defining the sprint tasks.
- Doing daily meetings to check what was done.
- Creating the Leads project in a Micro-frontend architecture.
- Creating the portability functionality for the army project.
- Doing month meeting with the frontend chapter.
- Creating unit and component's tests.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I work with: React, React context, testing-library, Jest, styled component, Material UI, NextJS, axios, Typescript, Azure, Kanban, Scrum, npm/yarn and git.

## Frontend developer | Apr. 2020 to Oct. | Agrotis

Working in the Agrotis Platform, I was the main frontend developer for the grain storage module, responsible in building new features and fixing bugs.

- Doing brainstorming to defining the sprint tasks.
- Doing daily meetings to check what was done.
- Adding typescritp to the project.
- Creating new components and pages with React and redux.
- Fixing bugs.
- Re-write class base components to functional components.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I work with: React, Redux, redux-form, react-hook-form, styled component, Material UI, react router, axios, Typescript, npm/yarn, git, Kanban, Scrum, bitbucket and Jira.

#### Full Stack Developer | Sep. 2014 - Feb. 2016 | PrimeLan Tecnologia

At Primelan I was responsible for creating web sites by demand, web apps that integrates with WIFI equipments for user authentication. I also created the Vitória Online, official android application for Vitória (ES) city.

- Doing brainstorming to planning the projects.
- Meeting clients to gathering information.
- Consuming web services from the city hall servers.
- Creating hot sites that integrates with WIFI equipments for users authentication.
- Building the Vitória Online native Android app.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: Java, Android SDK, Google Maps API, PHP, MySql, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, RESTfull API, JSON, Git, Adobe Fireworks e Adobe Illustrator.

#### Full Stack Developer | Nov. 2012 - Sep. 2014 | Megawork

My first task was to help building a suppliers pricing application which integrates with SAP. Later I worked building web sites and web applications that reads data from SAP.

- Doing meetings with clients and managers to gather projects details.
- Doing braimstorming to define the applications features.
- Creating services to connect and consuming data from SAP.
- Using .Net/C# to build backend features and HTML, CSS and javascript for building interfaces.
- Creating reports with Cristal Report.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 3.5, C#, SQLServer, PostGreSQL, SAP .Net Connector, .Net Web Services, SAP, ABAP, SOAP, HTML, CSS, Javascript and Git.

As .Net developer I worked in a web application for managing schools and universities, correcting bug's, creating custom features and training users.

- Working with Kanban to managing tasks.
- Developing custom features for clients.
- Fixing bugs reported by the clients.
- Working with the development team to create new features and updating the application version.
- Upgrading code to use .Net 3.5 features.
- Updating interfaces with Javascript libraries to improve users experience.
- Training new users, helping clients with custom and new features.
- Creating new database scripts and tables.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 2.0 - 3.5, C#, SQLServer, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery and others, SVN e Windows Team Foudation.

# .Net Developer | Jun. 2011 - Feb. 2012 | Superius Consultoria LTDA

At Superius I was part of the a team that was building ERP system using .Net 3.0, C#, DevExpress and Entity Framework.

- Doing meetings with the client for gathering information for developing the system modules.
- Working with the development team to analyze data and create tasks.
- · Creating database queries and tables.
- Creating libraries and base classes for general use.
- Creating custom interfaces using DevExpress library.
- Removing DevExpress library from some pages and implement lightweight javascript libraries to improve web pages performances.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 2.0 - 3.5, C#, SQLServer, DevExpress, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery e SVN.

### Junior .Net Developer | Jan. 2010 - Jul. 2011 | Vixtime

At Vixtime my first task was to helped building a News application and website, then I worked in the creation of CMS systems and websites by demand following the W3C standards.

- Doing brainstorming to debate ideas about projects and campaigns.
- Creating business logic, SQL queries and interfaces for the ES Hoje News application.
- Creating web sites by demand with HTML, CSS e Javascript following W3C web standards.
- Doing cuts and exporting images using Adobe Fireworks.
- Creating and customize CMS systems for clients.
- Helping the graphic designer to implement Adobe Flash animations and features using AS3.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 2.0, C#, SQLServer, HTML, CSS, Javascript (Jquery and others), Visual Studio, Adobe Fireworks e Adobe Dreamweaver.